- [Instructor] Hi, and welcome back.
In this section, we're
going to look at Git.
And the first thing we
have to do is download Git.
To download Git for Mac,
just go to git-scm.com/download/mac,
and that will begin the download,
and you can instal it like
any other normal programme,
and then it will be
accessible via your Terminal.
There are also many
graphical interfaces for Git,
and towards the end
I will be recommending
one of them as well,
but I think it's important
to start with the Terminal,
so that we know how Git really
works behind the scenes.
If you're on Windows,
then go to git-for-windows.github.io,
and download the Git Windows thing here.
This provides a terminal
that lets you run Git,
and also a number of other commands
that are normally not present in Windows.
So download that.
And let's look at how you would
download and instal this Git SCM.
So I'm going to go over to my virtual box,
and just to guide you through it.
If you're using a Mac, by the way,
you can just skip to the end.
If you're using Windows,
you may want to stay.
So launch Chrome,
go to git-for-windows.github.io,
and download that.
And then that would
start the download there.
I'm just going to speed through.
Once that's done, just press it to instal.
And then you can press Next.
And here, this is an important thing,
make sure to press
this Associate .sh files
to be run with Bash.
The other stuff, I would
also leave pressed,
and you may even want to get
their icon on the desktop
as well.
And then I would leave the
first option pressed here,
Use Git from Git Bash only.
You can, if you want, use this one,
Use Git from the Windows Command Prompt,
but I would recommend the first one.
If you use the second
one, then you can use
the default Windows
Command Prompt to run Git,
but the Windows Command
Prompt is lacking a few things
that you would want from your terminal,
so I would recommend always using
the programme that this is installing,
and leaving the option as number one.
And finally, I would also leave
the first one pressed here.
And I would also leave the
first one pressed here.
This is just which sort
of console it's using.
Leave that pressed there.
And finally, these two you
can leave pressed if you want.
They're not really going to make
much of a difference for us.
When that's done, you can
uncheck View Release Notes,
and check Launch Git Bash.
And that brings you to
this nice-looking terminal.
It's trying to log in right
now as your Windows user.
And my Windows computer is very slow.
Yours will be a bit faster.
And there you are.
You have, essentially
what we've got on the Mac.
Many of the things that we do on Mac
work on this terminal,
but they won't work on the
Windows command line.
So make sure to use this terminal
whenever you are interacting with Git.
And that's it.
Now you can continue, and follow
the videos along as usual.
And don't worry that we're
using Mac on the videos.
All of the commands
work the same way here.
So that's it.
Thanks for watching, and I'll
see you on the next video.